C.G. Jung
By the way, what've you been up to, Haruki?
I don't like this.
O-Oh, nothing...
Hey, if we put in positive
votes for each other...
Shh!
Don't talk about that stuff in the classroom.
Damn it. This atmosphere sucks.
Is it just gonna be like this until the vote?
Everyone's desperate to keep
their heads down before the vote.
Or they're trying to form cliques to
pass positive votes between themselves.
Maybe that's the only way after all.
You haven't mustered up the
determination to cut someone loose?
You're talking like Ryuen-kun now?
You claimed that Ryuen's
attitude was false confidence,
but it's your determination
that seems false to me.
What was that?
So? What do you intend to do?
I...
My inability to contribute to
the class is the result of
my lack of faith in my own leadership.
Brother... how should I face this?
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Could we meet up in the dorms this evening?
I'd like to discuss something with you.
Hey, Ayanokoji-kun.
On your way home?
Asahina-senpai?
Not with Honami today?
Ichinose and I aren't especially close.
Aren't you?
She claims you're friends.
What do you want?
You're right to the point.
But that's all right.
There's something I want to tell
you about our sweet Honami.
In the upcoming special exam...
She asked Miyabi for help.
President Nagumo?
They need twenty million points
to save someone from expulsion.
She's asked him to lend her the difference.
And what do you think Miyabi told her?
Did he require some kind of harsh condition?
The condition for lending her the points...
is for her to date him.
Are you sure you want to tell me this?
I'm doing it to help my own class.
If Miyabi lends that many
points to a first-year,
it could be a burden to us later.
And most of all...
I'd feel bad for Honami if she put herself
through that to help out a friend.
Why did you come to me about this?
I'm not sure.
I just thought you might be
able to do something about it.
Well...
It's like sending out a prayer
just in case, kind of.
Anyway, now you have the story.
You can decide what to do with it.
Sorry to take up your time like this.
I'm not bothered.
Well, let's not just stand around here.
We can talk in my room.
My, what a coincidence.
If it isn't the boys, Hirata and Ayanokoji.
Koenji-kun?
Rack those brains to figure out a
way through this exam, would you?
You never change, do you?
This exam isn't enough to change me.
While licking wounds with your comrades,
see that you take out the unneeded trash.
Ayanokoji-kun, let's go.
Okay.
The year's almost over, huh?
We were sent to a deserted
island, a training camp...
It's been a busy year.
Yeah. But I've enjoyed it.
And the class has come together so
much more than I would have thought
based on that first day.
Yeah.
Well... until this test started, anyway.
I thought it might be about that.
I'm sorry.
I just can't think of a way around this test.
No matter how hard I think about it.
Is there really no way
to save the entire class?
I'm afraid I can't think of one.
Getting twenty million points
together isn't a realistic option.
Yeah.
The only point of this test is to cut
out someone we don't need around.
But Hirata will never be willing
to figure out who that should be.
Hey, Ayanokoji-kun...
Do you think there's anyone in
particular we can do without?
Not in particular.
Whoever we lose,
we'll just have to deal with it.
You're very cool-headed.
You're better suited to
be class leader than me.
You think too highly of me.
You're too modest.
I've genuinely thought that since
the incident with Karuizawa-san.
Sorry to call you out at this hour.
Hey, that's fine.
But it's unusual for you
to ask to speak with me.
I really wanted to talk to you in person.
The floor is cold,
so feel free to sit on the bed.
Th-Thank you.
This is weirdly exciting...
How do you intend to approach this exam?
Well... I'm still thinking over ways to keep
someone from being expelled, I guess.
I thought you might ask
President Nagumo for help.
What kind of help?
I doubt even Class B is able to
round up twenty million points.
Which means you'd need
the aid of a third party.
I see.
Asahina-senpai told you?
Did she tell you his condition, too?
Yeah.
It's ridiculous, right? In all kinds of ways.
Thanks.
How many points shy are you?
A little over four million.
That's quite a bargain, then.
Yeah.
It seems absurd that Nagumo-senpai
would be willing to lend me that much
just because I dated him.
Honestly, it feels like the kind of thing
I'd have to spend points on to get.
I think this might be the only
way to save everyone in Class B.
Is it?
You're not judging me?
I see nothing to judge you for.
Though I don't understand why you're
so desperate to save one person.
I guess... you were worried about me, then?
I'm sure you think it's presumptuous of me.
That's not true. It makes me really happy.
But...
It might be a little troublesome for me.
If I hadn't talked to you, I might have
been able to make up my mind more easily.
Hey, Ayanokoji-kun...
Are you actually pretty amazing?
I'm afraid I don't feel that way.
But that makes you even more amazing!
Because you're just...
What is it?
It's nothing.
What was that about?
Are you serious?
What, have I ever lied to you?
Should we go together after class, then?
Sure, let's do it.
Did something happen?
Do you feel it, too?
I don't think I like it.
They were so on edge before,
but now something's different.
A group consensus has formed
on eliminating someone, maybe?
I see.
Now that you mention it,
it did feel that way.
Should we have someone investigate?
No, sniffing around could result
in one of us being targeted.
You think the target might
already be someone in our group?
D-Don't say that, Haruka-chan!
The fact that no one's asked us to
join their consensus suggests that
that might be the case.
If they threatened you to help
them or be targeted yourself...
What would you do?
I'd prioritize our own group, of course.
Even if it results in you becoming the target?
W-Well...
I just don't want to stay here so
badly it's worth betraying a friend.
I'd never betray you guys, either!
Keisei?
I theoretically agree with the two girls.
But reality isn't that kind.
"Embrace expulsion to help a friend"
has a beautiful ring to it,
but it would be painful to enact.
Hirata-kun...
What is it?
We've got an emergency situation.
The class is on the verge of expelling you.
Oh?
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
"Oh"? Did you know already?
No, this is the first I've heard of it.
So how can you be so calm?
Do you know how many intend to vote for me?
Not sure.
It feels like close to half might be in favor.
That's difficult.
Seriously, what are you gonna do?
I mean... you can do something, right?
I'll start to think that over.
You're such a space case.
They totally would've expelled
you if I weren't here to help.
This kind of situation is
exactly why you are here.
O-Oh?
I'm glad you told me.
Thank you, Kei.
Y-Yeah, you'd better be grateful.
I'll call you again some time later.
R-Right, got it.
Is he really gonna be okay?
I had a feeling you might
ask to speak with me!
I want to know who the ringleader
is in the plot against me.
Sorry, but I just can't tell you that.
I'm the only one who knows
who it is, after all.
So that's how it works?
That's my Ayanokoji-kun!
You already knew?
The ringleader talked to you first.
Then you used your people skills
to spread the idea among classmates
who aren't close to me.
It was a hard decision for me, too, you know?
I don't want to see you expelled...
But I can't betray the trust of
someone who confided in me.
I guess you won't tell me, then?
Sorry to call you out so late.
Aw... You gave up that easily?
Are you gonna track down
the ringleader yourself?
I'm not sure. I probably can't.
Fine, then, I'll tell you!
The ringleader is Yamauchi-kun.
I see.
Satisfied now?
The real ringleader is Sakayanagi, then?
You figured out that much?
I doubt Yamauchi could convince you to
stick your neck out to play mediator.
And Sakayanagi did come by
to visit Yamauchi earlier.
Well, I did want to avoid getting
on Sakayanagi-san's bad side.
This has been helpful, Kushida.
Do your best not to get expelled, okay?
What is it?
There's something I want you to do.
Very well. I'll take measures tomorrow.
Thanks.
Horikita Manabu
You don't have any regrets?
I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
How long has it been since
we spoke alone like this?
Outside of when I first joined the school,
it would be three years.
I see. That sounds correct.
If you're seeking points to help
you in the supplementary exam,
you're wasting your time.
I'm not.
I wasn't going to ask for...
that kind of support.
Brother, please... give me courage.
For this exam,
everyone's either keeping their head
down and waiting for it to be over,
or desperately forming groups
to try to control the vote.
In both cases,
they're turning their eyes away from the
pressure of choosing someone to expel.
But if we do it that way,
I think we'll regret it someday.
That's why I...
I want to face it.
I want to face this exam head-on,
and find an answer I can accept.
I'd like to ask you one question.
How has your time at school been?
Enjoyable?
W-Well...
I'm sorry. I...
I genuinely don't know if I'd call it enjoyable.
But... it's not boring.
I see.
It seems you've conquered one of your flaws.
You never looked at anything around you.
But you've widened your view, and
you're escaping your life of boredom.
This doesn't sound much like you.
What would sound like me?
All you see of me is my
achievements and popularity.
That's because... you are my eternal goal.
Your goal?
How do you see Ayanokoji, then?
He's a classmate I don't particularly care for.
But... he's someone I want to
catch up to and surpass someday.
I'm sorry to say, but you
won't catch up to Ayanokoji.
That said, you don't have to.
You should grow in a way
that's more like you.
"Like me"?
Are you afraid?
I am.
In order to close this distance,
you must take a step forward.
What do I do?
You are still naïve,
but I will give you the answer.
So tell me what it is you
want to ask your class.
I will.
The supplementary exam is tomorrow.
You'd better not sleep through it.
We'd never do that!
Right?
Dismissed, then.
Yamauchi's strategy wasn't a bad one.
His one mistake was listening to Sakayanagi
and choosing me as his target.
Now, move, Horikita.
You should be capable of it now.
If you'll excuse me, everyone.
I'd like a minute of your time.
What's this all about, Horikita-san?
There's something I want to say
to you regarding tomorrow's vote.
Where's this coming from?
H-Hey, what's this all about?
Me and Kanji have plans to hang out, so...
Someone could be expelled tomorrow.
Yet you're awfully calm, aren't you?
W-Well, I guess...
I've made my peace with it?
That's very admirable,
but what I have to say only
matters if you're all here.
These last few days,
I've been thinking it over.
Who should remain? Who should be expelled?
And today I was able to find the answer.
So I want to tell you that here.
Wait, Horikita-san.
Nobody here deserves to be expelled!
Please allow me to finish.
I had my doubts at first, too.
The nature of this test means we
can't even talk things out in class.
It's become a battle to form
groups to control the vote.
True.
As a result, there's a chance that an
excellent student who should
remain could be expelled.
That wouldn't be any kind of exam.
I don't know what's come over you,
but this is unexpectedly logical reasoning.
Tell us more, would you?
About what you would do.
Normally, I'd like to talk with all
of you and decide who to expel.
But that would be difficult in practice.
Therefore...
I will name the person who
deserves to be expelled.
Don't do that!
You're just going to confuse everyone!
We can at least hear her out first.
I agree with Red Hair-kun.
The one I believe should
be expelled on this exam...
Yamauchi Haruki-kun...
It's you.